John Clarke Slater Papers 1908-1976 Mss.B.SL2p
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1908-1976; 45 lin. feet (Box 1-89)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology
    - Project D.I.C.
    - Proposal to the advanced research projects agency
    - Proposed physics program for the research laboratory of electronics
    - Proposed research program in nuclear physics of the physics department
    - Quarterly progress report
    - Radioactivity center
    - Research appointments in the post-war period
    - Research and development task order contract
    - Research associates
    - Research fiscal office
    - Research in progress
    - Research laboratory of electronics
    - Research programs in physics
    - Seminar on atomic power
    - Schedule for visits to laboratories by foreign guests
    - Spectroscopy laboratory
    - Weekly calendar
  - Master Charge
  - Mastick, Donald F
  - Materials Center
  - Materials Research
  - Materials Research Bulletin
  - Materials Research Laboratory
  - Matheson, J A L
  - Matlow, Sheldon
  - Matsen, F A
  - Mattheiss, Leonard F
  - Matthews, D R
  - Matthews, Samuel A
  - Matthias, Bernd T
  - Mattill, John I
  - Mattis, Daniel
  - Maruer, Robert
  - Mauritz, Kenneth A
  - Mautz, Robert B
  - Maxwell, Louis R
  - May, Madeline
  - Mayer, Gerard C
  - Mayer, J A
  - Mayer, Joseph E
  - Maxwell, E
  - Maxwell, I R
  - Mayer-Kaupp, H
  - Mazur, Paul
  - Meador, Willard E, Jr.
  - Meadow, Henry
  - Meadows, Paul
  - Meckler, Alvin
  - Megaw, Helen D
  - Mehra, Jagdish
  - Meier, Walter
  - Memoranda
  - Mendelssohn, K
  - Mendenhall, C E
  - Merrifield, Donald P
  - Merritt, Ernest
  - Mesitch, Antonio A
  - Metallurgical Society of American Institute of Mining Engineers
  - Meyer, Axel
  - Meyer, E Gerald
  - Micha, David A
  - Michaels, Alan S
  - Michel, Louis.
  - Mid-Century Convocation on the Social Implications of Scientific Progress
  - Midwinter Solid State Research Conference
  - Mikami, H M
  - Milbank, Jeremiah, Jr.
  - Miller, Bruce
  - Miller, Edward F
  - Miller, Freeman D
  - Miller, M R
  - Miller, P H
  - Millikan, Robert A
  - Millman, Sidney
  - Millsaps, Knox
  - Mineralogical Society of America
  - Minnhagen, Lennart
  - Miscellaneous notes
  - Miscellaneous notes (Physics)
  - Mitchell, J W
  - Mittleman, Marvin H
  - Miyake, Shizuo
  - Mock, Willis, Jr.
  - Modern Physics correspondence
  - Moe, Henry Allen
  - Moeira, Manoel da Frota
  - Moffitt, William
  - Mohr, Franklin
  - Molecular structure and spectra
  - Montgomery, D J
  - Montroll, Elliott
  - Mooney, Rose C L [Mrs. John C. Slater]
  - Moore, Clara E
  - Moore, Clifford H
  - Moore, D C
  - Moore, Walter J
  - Morita, Akira
  - Morrish, A H
  - Morse, Philip M
  - Morse, R W
  - Morrison, William
  - Morss, Everett
  - Moscowitz, Albert
  - Moser, Carl
  - Moskowitz, Jules W
  - Moss, Edith
  - Motorola, Inc.
  - Mott, N F
  - Mott, Sir Nevil
  - Mourad, Pierre
  - Mrozowski, S
  - Mueller, Charles R
  - Muldane, Leonard
  - Muldawer, Leonard
  - Müller, Hans (also Mueller)
  - Mulligan, Joseph F
  - Mulliken, Robert S
  - Mullin, Charles J
  - Mundie, Lloyd G
  - Muran, L E
  - Murphy, Glenn
  - Murphy, Priscilla
  - Murray, John R
  - Murray Printing Company
  - Muschlitz, Earle E, Jr.
  - Musher, Jeremy I
  - Mutch, W W
  - Muto, Tashinosuke
  - Nabarro, F R N
  - Nachtrieb, Norman H
  - Nagamiya, T
  - Naiman, Charles S
  - Nambara, Shigeru
  - Nasanow, Lew H
  - Nassau Tavern
  - Natapoff, Marshall
  - National Academy of Sciences
    - Abelson, Philip Hauge
    - Adams, Roger
    - Allison, Samuel K
    - Bacher, Robert F
    - Bainbridge. K. T.
    - Bardeen, John
    - Beams, J W
    - Bearden, Joyce Avin
    - Birge, Raymond T
    - Bloch, Felix
    - Bonner, Tom Wilkerson
    - Breit, Gregory
    - Brillouin, Leon
    - Brode, Robert B
    - Brode, Wallace Reed
    - Bronk, Detlev W
    - Brooks, Harvey
    - Coblentz, W W
    - Compton, Arthur H
    - Compton, Karl T
    - Constitution and by-laws
    - Dennison, David Mathias
    - Du Bridge, L A
    - Du Mond, Jesse W M
    - Epstein, Paul L
    - Feynman, Richard Phillips
    - Fuson, R C
    - Gamow, George
    - Goldhaber, Maurice
    - Halpern, Otto
    - Harrison, George R
    - Haworth, Leland John
    - Herb, Raymond George
    - Herzfeld, Karl Ferdinand
    - Hofstadter, Robert
    - Home Secretary
    - Hornig, Donald Frederick
    - Houston, W V
    - Hughes, Arthur Llewelyn
    - Johnson, Thomas Hope
    - Kelly, M J
    - Kent, R H
    - Kingdom, Kenneth H
    - Knudsen, Vern Oliver
    - Kusch, Polykarp
    - Lamb, Willis Eugene
    - Land, Edwin H
    - Lindsay, Robert Bruce
    - Mayer, Maria Goeppert
    - Meggers, William Frederick
    - Meid, G D
    - Members of the section of physics
    - Millikan, Robert A
    - Mitchell, Allan Charles Gray
    - Morse, Philip McCord
    - Street, Jabez Curry
    - Struve, Otto
    - Thomas, Llewellyn Hilleth
    - Townes, Charles Hard
    - Van Vleck, J H
    - Warren, Bertram Eugene
    - Weisskopf, Victor Frederick
    - Wetmore, Alexander
    - Wheeler, John Archibald
    - Wilson, Edwin B
    - Wilson, E B
    - Zacharias, Jerrold Reinach
  - National Academy of Science-National Research Council. Solid State Sciences Panel
  - National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics
  - National Aeronautics and Space Administration
  - National Cyclopedia of American Biography
  - National Defence Research Council Micro-Committee
  - National Medal of science
  - National Nuclear Science Laboratory
  - National Research Council
  - National Research Council - Canada
  - National Science Foundation
  - Nature
  - Neel, L
  - Neema, D G
  - Neher, Henry Victor
  - Neilly, Andrew H, Jr.
  - Nemoshkalenko, V V
  - Nesbet, Robert K
  - Nettel, Stephen J
  - Nevis, Arnold H
  - New England Merchants National Bank
  - Newcomer, N B
  - Newell, J S
  - Newhouse Corporation of America
  - Newton, Amos
  - Nicholas, John F
  - Nielsen, Harald H
  - Nielsen, Walter M
  - Nigam, Amar Nath
  - Nile, Stephen W, Jr.
  - 1967 International Congress on Magnetism
  - Ninth International Conference on Quantum Electronics
  - Nishina, Y
  - Nitka, H F
  - Nobel Committee for Chemistry
  - Nobel Committee for Physics
  - Nobel Prize Committees
  - Nolte, Hans Jürgen
  - Nordling, Carl
  - Norman, Joseph G, Jr.
  - Norris, Charles H
  - North, Dwight O
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization. Advanced Study Institute
  - North-Holland Publishing Company
  - Norton, C L
  - Norwood, Lawrence
  - Nosomow, Lewis H
  - Nottingham, E
  - Nottingham, J Peter
  - Nottingham, Wayne B
  - Nowacki, W
  - Nowak, David A
  - Nowak, Welville B
  - Nowik, I
  - Nuclear Science and Engineering
  - Oak Ridge Associated Universities
  - Oak Ridge National Laboratory
  - O'Connell, Kathleen A
  - Odabasi, H
  - O'Donnell, George A
  - Office of Emergency Management
  - Office of Naval Research
  - Office of Scientific Research
  - Ohno, Kimio
  - Oklahoma State University
  - O'Konski, Chester T
  - Old, B S
  - Oldenberg, O
  - Olson, Alvin Russell
  - Omar, M A
  - Omar, Syed Iqbal
  - Oosterhoff, L J
  - Opera Group, Inc., Boston, Mass.
  - Operational Reasoning, Reality, and Quantum Mechanics
  - Oppenheim, Irwin
  - Orbach, Raymond L
  - Orbán, G
  - Ordnance Materials Research Office
  - Orgel, Leslie E
  - Oriani, R A
  - Orowan, Egon
  - Osgood, Thomas H
  - Osborn, John A
  - Otter, Frederick A, Jr.
  - Otting, William J
  - Outline of book
  - Overhage, Carl F J
  - Owen, Walter S
  - Owens, Herbert D
  - Oyama, Seiichi
  - Page, N C
  - Paić, M
  - Paine, T O
  - Painter, Gayle S
  - Pais, A
  - Palke, William E
  - Palmer, Edward
  - Palmer, R Ronald
  - Palmer, Whitfield M, Jr.
  - Palo'oz, I
  - Pan, Yuh Kang
  - Panofsky, Wolfgang Kurt Hermann
  - Pantelides, Sokrates T
  - Parada, Nelson J
  - Park, Joseph H
  - Parker House
  - Parker, Vincent E
  - Parks, George
  - Parmenter, Robert H
  - Parr, Robert G
  - Parratt, L G
  - Parrish, William
  - Parrott, John
  - Parry, C F
  - Parseghian, Nuvart
  - Parzen, G
  - Patel, J C
  - Patterson, A L
  - Patterson, R A
  - Paul, David I
  - Pauling, Linus
  - Pearson, William B
  - Peat, F David
  - Pegram, George B
  - Pekeris, C L
  - Pelah, I
  - Pellam, John R
  - Pelletier, S W
  - Pelzer, Ethel
  - Peninsula Motor Club
  - Pentz, M J
  - Pepinsky, Ray
  - Pereira, José R
  - Pergamon Press
  - Perkins, Enid E
  - Perkins, Granville A
  - Perrin, F H
  - Perspectives for computation of electronic structure in ordered and disoriented solids: See: Grimardi, François
  - Perspectives in spectroscopy
  - Peters, David
  - Peterson, Rudolph E
  - Peyerimhoff, Sigrid
  - Phelan, John K
  - Phelps, Everett
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Univ.of Fla.)
  - Philip, John F
  - Phillips, G C
  - Phillips, J C
  - Phillips, Lindsay F
  - Phillips, Sidney L
  - Photographs
  - Physical Chemistry
  - Physical Review
  - Physical Society
  - Physical Society of Japan
  - Physicists and bibliographies
  - Physics Abstracts
  - The Physics Teacher
  - Physics Today
  - Pierce, G W
  - Pietronero, Luciano
  - Piller, Herbert
  - Pines, David
  - Piore, Maxine
  - Pipkin, F M
  - Pippard, Brian
  - Pitzer, Kenneth S
  - Plaskett, Harry H
  - Plass, Gilbert N
  - Platt, John R
  - Plendl, Hans S
  - Plenum Publishing Corporation
  - Plesset, Ernst
  - Plugge, John A
  - Platzman, Robert L
  - Poindexter, Richard G
  - Pogany, A P
  - Polakowski, N H
  - Poland, Robert
  - Polder, D
  - Polhemus, Robert B
  - Pollard, William G
  - Pople, J A
  - Porter, Charles E
  - Porter, Jack D
  - Position paper for the Boulder Conference
  - Posner, Gary H
  - Post, B
  - Potential energy curve for the vibrational energy of the N-alpha-2 molecule
  - Potter, A A
  - Potter, A C
  - Potter, James G
  - Potts, R B
  - Pound, Robert Vivian
  - Powell, Alice
  - Powell, Wilson M
  - Power, James D
  - Power series methods for cellular calculations on atoms, molecules, and solids
  - Powers, Philip N
  - Prasad, S S
  - Prasad, Shiva
  - Pratt, George W, Jr.
  - Preier, Horst
  - Prentice-Hall, Inc.
  - Prescott, Samuel C
  - President's Committee on the National Medal of Science
  - Price, Fraser P
  - Price, P J
  - Primakoff, Henry
  - Princeton University
  - Proctor, Redfield
  - Professors R.D. Bennett, D.C.Jackson, Hans Muller, J.C.Slater
  - Progress of theoretical physics
  - Properties of single crystals
  - Proposal for the establishment of a north-eastern regional laboratory for nuclear science and engineering
  - Proposal for extension of Contract N50R1-D7856.
  - Proposal for support of basic research in solid-state and molecular structure
  - Proposal for support of the solid-state and molecular theory group
  - Proposal to the National Science Foundation. Advanced science seminar program
  - Proskauer, Eric S
  - Prosser, Franklin
  - Provident Institution for Savings
  - Prowse, Derek J.
  - Pruett Press, Inc.
  - Pryce, M H L
  - Pugh, David
  - Pullman, Bernard
  - Purcell, E M
  - Pusey, Nathan M
  - QCPE
  - Quadrangle Club
  - Quimby, S L
  - Quinton, Arthur R
  - Quitter, W M
  - Rabi, I I
  - Raccah, Paul M
  - Radford, W H
  - Radiation damage
  - Radiation damage survey
  - Radium
  - Rado, George T
  - Ragey
  - Raimes, S
  - Rakestraw, Norris W
  - Ralph, D C
  - Ramasastry, C
  - Raman, C V
  - Ramberg, E G
  - Ramsey, Norman F
  - Rand Corporation
  - Randall, H M
  - Ransil, Bernard J
  - Rao, D V G L Narasikha
  - Rathenau, G W
  - Rawls, Walter C, Jr.
  - Ray, D K
  - Raymond, F H
  - Raytheon Manufacturing Company
  - Rayudu, T Venkala
  - Read, Thornton
  - Redfield, Alfred C
  - Reed, William A
  - Rees, A L G
  - Reeves, C M
  - Reich, Theodore
  - Reiche, F
  - Reichle, Leonard F
  - Reidel, D., Publishing Company
  - Reitz, John R
  - Reichardt, W
  - Reinsch, E A
  - Reitz, J Wayne
  - Remarks on the Overlapping Sphere Method for Molecular Orbitals
  - Renninger, M
  - Renwick, Mary E
  - Reprint schedule
  - Republication National Committee
  - Research Corporation
  - Responsibilities of health-physics
  - Restaurant "En Plein Ciel" (autographed menu)
  - Reviews of Modern Physics
  - Reynolds, J M
  - Reynolds, Neva E
  - Rhind, D L
  - Rhyan, Walter R
  - Rhyins, Richard W
  - Rice, E E
  - Rice, Oscar
  - Rice, Stuart A
  - Richards, A N
  - Richardson, Charles L., & Company
  - Richardson, Elizabeth P
  - Richardson, James W
  - Richtmyer, F K
  - Rickaysen, Gerald
  - Riedinger, R
  - Rieser, Leonard M, Jr.
  - Riess, Ilan
  - Rigden, John S
  - Riley, Robert J
  - Rimmer, Dennis E
  - Ringers, Douglas A
  - Rizzo, Don
  - Roberts, Art
  - Roberts, Benjamin W
  - Roberts, G A
  - Roberts, P J
  - Roberts, Robert A
  - Roberts, Shepard
  - Robertson, David S
  - Robertson, J Monteath
  - Robertson, R M
  - Robertson, W D
  - Robin, M B
  - Robinson, Eugene S
  - Robson, Hugh
  - Rockefeller Fund expenditures
  - Rockefeller Research Fund Committee
  - Rockefeller Unversity
  - Rodebush, W H
  - Rodman, James P
  - Rogers, A P
  - Rogers, Eric M
  - Rohrlich, F
  - Rojansky, V
  - Roothaan, C C J
  - Ros, Pieter
  - Rose, A J
  - Roseman, Jack
  - Roseman, Saul
  - Rosen, Philip
  - Rosenberg, Arthur J
  - Rosenfeld, Leon
  - Rosenkrans, James P, Jr.
  - Rosental, Stefan
  - Ross, E E
  - Ross, Marvin
  - Rossby, C G
  - Rossi, Bruno
  - Roth, Walter L
  - Rothschild Prizes Organization in Israel
  - Rosen, Philip
  - Rosenberg, Arthur J
  - Rosenfeld, Leon
  - Rosenkrans, James P, Jr.
  - Rosental, Stefan
  - Ross, E E
  - Ross, Marvin
  - Rossby, C G
  - Rossi, Bruno
  - Roth, Walter L
  - Rothschild Prizes Organization in Israel
  - Rowlands
  - Roy, R R
  - Ruark, Arthur
  - Ruderman, Sheldon
  - Rudge, William E
  - Ruedenberg, Klaus
  - Runciman, W Alan
  - Russell, B R
  - Russell, H W
  - Russell, John R
  - Ruth, Marion
  - Ruthven, Jean A
  - Ryan, W P
  - Ryan, J E
  - Rychlewski, Jacek
  - Ryder, Francis B
  - Sachs, Mendel
  - Sack, Robert
  - Sadanaga, R
  - Saffren, Melvin M
  - Sagalyn, Paul L
  - Sagamore Conference
  - Sagamore Conference on charge and spin density
  - Sagamore Conference register, 1971 April
  - Sagamore Conference II
  - Sagamore Conference III
  - Sage, N McL
  - Saha, M N
  - Saharia, G S
  - Sahni, R C
  - Saint John's College, Cambridge
  - Salié, H
  - Salisburg, Franklin C
  - Saltonstall, Leverett
  - Samuel, A L
  - Sandia Corporation
  - Sanibel-Captiva Planning Board, Inc.
  - Sanibel Island home (house)
  - Sanibel-Captiva Real Estate
  - Sauer, John ASaunders, Frederick A
  - Saunders, W. B., Company
  - Sandia Corporation
  - Sandorfy, C
  - Saxon, David S
  - Sayers, Ralph A
  - Saylor, J H
  - Schamp, Homer W, Jr.
  - Schein, Marcel
  - Scherr, Adelaide
  - Scherr, Charles W
  - Scherrer, P
  - Schiff, Leonard I
  - Schlömann, Ernst
  - Schlosser, Herbert
  - Schlosser, H. Composite wave variational method for solution of the energy band problem in solids
  - Schmitt, G P
  - Schneider, W G
  - Schnelle, R N
  - Schools of the ARPA Interdisciplinary Materials Science Program
  - Schor, Robert
  - Schottky, W
  - Schrader, David M
  - Schriber, James C
  - Schrieffer, J Robert
  - Schultz, Theodore D
  - Schutte, C J H
  - Schwabl, Franz
  - Schwartz, Jacob T
  - Schwarz, Karlheinz
  - Schweinler, Harold C
  - Science (magazine)
  - Scientists and engineers for Humphrey-Muskie
  - Scott, James F
  - Scovil, Georgiana
  - Scully, Marlan O
  - Sears, Ray E J
  - Seaver, W N
  - Second Canadian Symposium on Quantum Chemistry (see also C. Sandorfy)
  - Second International Congress of Crystal-lography
  - Second International Congress of Quantum Chemistry
  - Second International Congress on Acoustics
  - Seeger, Alfred
  - Segall, Benjamin
  - Seegitz, Barbara C
  - Segerman, Ephraim
  - Segré, Emilio
  - Seitz, Frederick
  - Serber, Robert
  - Serin, Bernard
  - Seminar notes, 1930
  - Sequeira, Manoel Lopes de
  - Seshagiri, N
  - Setze, Kathryn
  - Severinghaus, W L
  - Shank, Russell
  - Shankland, R S
  - Shapira, Yoram
  - Shapley, Harlow
  - Sharma, K C
  - Sharma, P K
  - Sharma, R R
  - Sharp, Edward R
  - Sharp, R T
  - Sahw, Burton E
  - Shea, Josephine
  - Shearin, Paul E
  - Shelton, W Neil
  - Shell Development Company
  - Shelter Island Conference on low temperatures
  - Shenstone
  - Shepard, W N
  - Shiffman, Carl A
  - Shimizu, Hirataro
  - Shockley, William
  - Shoemaker, David P
  - Shoenberg, David
  - Shot-effect for photoelectrons
  - Shrock, Robert R
  - Shrum, G M
  - Shugurou, V
  - Shull, C.G.
    - Final technical report: Research on the use of polarized neutron beams
    - Neutron diffraction and neutron physics studies
  - Shull, Clifford Glenwood
  - Shull, Cliff, and Martha
  - Shull, Harrison
  - Shulman, Robert G
  - Shutts, L W
  - Shyu, Wei-Mei
  - Siegbahn, Kai
  - Siegel, Sidney
  - Sigma Xi
  - Sikand, Mahinder Singh
  - Silber, John R
  - Silverio, Miroslav
  - Silverman, Jerry
  - Silverman, Shirleigh
  - Silversmith, Donald J
  - Silverstein, Abe
  - Silverstone, Harris J
  - Simmons, Ralph O
  - Simon, F E
  - Simon & Schuster, Inc.
  - Simonds, J C
  - Simons, John C
  - Simpson, Russell W
  - Sinanoglu, Oktay
  - Singer, K
  - Singh Sikand, Mahinder
  - Sinnott, M J
  - Siqueira, Manoel Lopes de
  - Sirota, N N
  - Sise, A F
  - Sisler, Harry H
  - Sivasankar, C
  - Sixth Canadian Symposium on Theoretical Chemistry
  - Sixth Washington Conference on Theoretical Physics
  - Skafte-Lindblom, Mrs. Saga
  - Skinner, H W B
  - Skolnikoff, W B
  - Slader, June E
  - Slater, Mrs. [mother]
  - Slater, Clarke Rothwell
  - Slater, Daniel
  - Slater, Fred
  - Slater, John Clarke
    - Appointment as Institute Professor
    - Article on physics department for TEN
    - Atomic, Molecular and Solid-State physics
    - Atomic Radii in crystals
    - An Augmented Plane Wave method for the periodic potential problem
    - Average energy of states of given multiplicities in atoms
    - Band theory of bonding in metals
    - Bibliography
    - Biographical sketch
    - Big molecules and energy
    - Blueprint for a "Center for solid-state and molecular science at MIT"
    - Bohr-Kramers-Slater after fifty years
    - Book reviews
    - Building blocks and structure design: Forecasting from atomic structure and periodic system
    - Calculation of the magnetization and total energy of vanadium as a function of lattice parameter
    - Cambridge talk on electrons in metals, 15 August 1960
    - Cellular TDF method for molecules and solids
    - A Combined Cellular-Muffin-Tin Method for the molecular and crystal problem
    - Commencement address, Ridon College
    - Comments on the correlation problem
    - [Comparison of Thomas-Fermi-Dirac and Multiple-Scattering X-alpha methods]
    - Comparison of TFD and X-alpha methods for molecules and solids
    - Concerning the X-alpha method for calculating energy bands of a number of metals
    - Congratulations on election to the National Academy of Sciences
    - Contracts
    - Correlation in the Free-Electron Gas
    - Correlation in Two-Electron systems
    - Correlation problems in solids
    - Course VIII - Students
    - Course VIII - Revision
    - Critical evaluation of the elctron theory of metals for Aime Seminar, 1952.
    - A derivation of the Lorentz transformation from the properties of matter, 1922.
    - Development of quantum mechanics in the period, 1924-1926.
    - Diffraction and solid-state physics
    - Discussion of Fermi-Thomas with exchange
    - Discussion of paper by Moffitt
    - Early versions of the quantum theory book
    - Electronic properties of solids. Galley proof
    - Energy band theory of magnetism
    - Energy bands in solids
    - Energy bands and the theory of solids
    - Energy bands calculations by the APW method
    - Excerpts from personal letters bearing to visit to Copenhagen, Spring 1924.
    - Exchange and correlation in the self-consistent field
    - Exchange expression in the HHF and X-alpha self-consistent field methods
    - Exchange in magnetic atoms
    - Exchange in spin-polarized energy bands
    - Exchange potential for electrons
    - Expense account
    - Fourian resolution
    - Future prospects for the S-alpha method
    - A generalized self-consistent field method
    - The Hellmann-Feynman and virial theorems in the X-alpha method
    - History and the theory of solid state physics
    - History of the MIT Physics Department
    - History of the S-alpha method
    - Illustrations
    - An improved augmented plane wave method for the periodic potential problem
    - The interaction of mechanical and electromagnetic waves in crystals
    - Interview, 1968
    - Interview by Charles Weiner, February 1970
    - Interview, correspondence re... by T.S.Kuhn, et al.
    - Interviews, transcripts of...by T.S.Kuhn and J.H.Van Vleck
    - Itinerary, 23 June 1948
    - Introduction of E. U. Condon, 22 January 1973
    - Introduction of J. H. Van Vleck, 1971
    - Introduction of L. H. Thomas, 1975.
    - Introduction to Chemical Physics (a review, unsigned)
    - Introduction to the theory of ferroelectricity
    - Larmon's theorem
    - Lecture for session on atoms as many-electron systems, 19 January 1970
    - Lecture for session on band theory
    - The long-range interaction of unlike atoms
    - Lorentz trans. from properties of matter
    - The man who lit the fuse
    - A materials center for MIT
    - Memoranda
    - Memorandum concerning the research program of J. C. Slater and associates at the University of Florida
    - Memorandum on the present state of particle accelerators
    - Memorandum on the research needs of the group working on the X-alpha method in the quantum theory project
    - Memorandum regarding cellular integrations - not for publication
    - Memorandum to Staff, 27 May 1946
    - Memos to Secretary
    - Miscellaneous memos
    - Miscellaneous notes (MIT. Dep't of physics)
    - M del dependencies of corrections to the Fermi function
    - Modern physics for engineers
    - Molecular integrals
    - Molecules and solids
    - Molecules, solids and surfaces
    - Morse's contributions to atomic, molecular and solid-state physics
    - Multiplets from a (D)2 configuration in a cubic external field
    - New methods in the theory of molecules and solids
    - Note on correlation and exchange in the X-alpha and Hedin-Lundqvist methods
    - Note on Green's function method
    - Note on superlattices and Brillouin zones
    - Note on the Free-electron exchange approximation
    - Note on the SCF-X-alpha-MS method and the energy crisis
    - Note on the space part of antisymmetric wave functions in the many-electron problem
    - Note on the structure of the 3d bands in iron group crystals
    - Notes for talk to Winter Institute, 28 December 1973.
    - Notes for lecture on the magnetron
    - Notesin quantum mechanics; examinations; problems and course
    - Old and new physics and its uses, 1937
    - On the MIT materials center
    - One-electron energies of atoms, molecules and solids
    - Open problems in the physics of solids
    - Outline for talk for University of Georgia, 26 March 1970
    - Outstanding trends in present quantum-mechanical methods
    - Overlapping spheres in the X-alpha method
    - Personal data
    - Philosophy and physics, 1937
    - Physics department and laboratory of nuclear physics
    - Physics graduate students in the last half century
    - Presentation of Bingham Medal to P. W. Bridgman
    - Proposal for a cooperative computing laboratory at MIT
    - Proposal for a grant for a program of research in the field of chemical and solid-state physics; MIT
    - Proposal for a molecular theory group in the physics department, MIT
    - Quantum calculation of crystal energies
    - Quantum electrodynamics at low frequencies, November 1948; (16 folders)
    - Quantum mechanics and ceramics
    - Quantum mechanics of electrons in metals